ALYSSA HELLRUNG, Ph.D.

alyssahellrung@gmail.com | (206)-940-8673 | Seattle, WA 98112 **LinkedIn:** https://tinyurl.com/y3po7j8z | **GitHub:** https://github.com/alyssahellrung| **Portfolio:** https://tinyurl.com/y6rfaugw

SUMMARY

University of Washington-educated full stack developer currently pursuing Web Developer or Software Engineer role. Excited to parlay extensive background in education into building dynamic web applications, web-based tools, and software. Creative problem solver, team player, attention to detail. Looking forward to exercising agility as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team committed to building intuitive and exciting experiences for all users on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, MySQL/Sequelize,

MongoDB/Mongoose, React, Python

Other Technologies: Bootstrap 4, Ulkit, API handling, Passport, Auth0, Git, Heroku, Microsoft

Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

PROJECTS

Pandemic Pantry

Github: https://tinyurl.com/pandemicpantry | **Deployed:** https://tinyurl.com/pantryhome

- A web app that allows users to search for recipes based on ingredients they have at home. Results can be tailored to fit dietary preferences and intolerances.
- Handled AJAX responses, UI/UX, and images
- HTML5, CSS/ZURB Foundation, Javascript, Spoonacular API, MediaWiki API

GetTask

Github: https://tinyurl.com/gettask | Deployed: https://calm-scrubland-27592.herokuapp.com/

- A web app that allows development or work teams to collaborate on and keep track of tasks, bugs, or other problems that need to be handled.
- Handled database, models, server, some routes, and project management.
- HTML5, CSS/Materialize, Javascript/jQuery, Node.js, Express, MySQL/Sequelize, Handlebars, Passport.

Vote Goat

Github: https://tinyurl.com/vgoat | Deployed: https://vote-goat.herokuapp.com/#/

- A web app that provides users with information about when, where, and how to vote in their area and gives them access to contact information about their representatives.
- Wrote models, server, all authorization and authentication, automated emails, and handled project management.
- HTML5, CSS/Ulkit, Javascript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB/Mongoose, React, Auth0, Google Civic API.

EXPERIENCE

Part-Time Lecturer University of Washington

2013–present Seattle, WA

Developed "Gender and Sport" course within the Gender, Women, and Sexuality Studies department in 2013 and taught 30-100 student sections ever since. Responsible for teaching students of diverse social identities and with varied learning styles. Continually update the course materials to reflect current events and trends. Manage and mentor teaching assistants. Was able to adapt in-person course to an online format with two weeks notice due to Coronavirus.

Key Accomplishments:

- Earned "highly meritorious" classification in each year of teaching.
- Mentored over 15 students to successful completion of independent research and thesis projects.

Aerial and Youth Companies Coach School of Acrobatics and New Circus Arts

2009–present Seattle, WA

Teaches classes in aerial arts to children, teens, and adults. Head coach of the youngest youth troupe within the SANCA Youth Companies. Extensive experience as a performer, manager, choreographer, and show director.

Key Accomplishments:

- Directed the flying trapeze program from its inception in 2009 until 2012.
- Wrote and directed three full-length circus shows.
- Attended American Youth Circus Organization (AYCO) Festivals in 2013, 2017, and 2019 with over a dozen youth performers from SANCA.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Washington, WA

Doctorate in Feminist Studies: University of Washington, WA

Bachelor of Arts in English and Gender Studies: University of Notre Dame, IN

ORGANIZATIONS

Inclusion, Diversity, Equity, Antiracism Committee (IDEA) at SANCA, Seattle, WA 2020-present

American Circus Educators Association (ACE) 2017-present